mtholyoke.edu 2015-06-27

# Website Privacy Statement | Mount Holyoke College

Mount Holyoke College values individuals’ privacy and is committed to protecting and keeping secure personal information obtained through the College’s websites. This statement explains how the information is gathered and used.

### Information collected and its uses

In an effort to improve the content of the Mount Holyoke College website, certain information may be collected when users browse our website. Some information is collected through the use of cookies—small files of data from a website that are stored in a user’s browser based on a user’s Internet Protocol (IP) address that is not linked to their email address or any personal information.

Cookies may be disabled by adjusting the setting of your browser, or by installing tools like Google’s [Opt-out Browser Add-on](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout), but this may impede the full functionality of the website making the user experience less engaging.

Some Mount Holyoke-owned and -affiliated websites use Google Analytics to track non-personal data such as IP address, language, geo-location, browser type and operating system, among other things. This is a Google web-analytics tool that also keeps track of website activity and users’ browsing habits such as duration of time spent on the site. See Google Analytics’ [terms of use](http://www.google.com/analytics/terms/us.html) and Google’s [privacy policy](http://www.google.com/policies/privacy/) for more information.

All the information is collected solely for internal use. We use it to track and evaluate traffic trends so that we can continually improve the quality our website, and the College might use this information to inform you of changes to MHC-owned and -affiliated websites or to provide you other news and information about the site that we believe may be of interest to you.

It is neither shared nor sold to third parties unless 1) you give us express consent; or 2) we are required to disclose it in compliance with state or federal laws.

### Links to external websites

For our users’ convenience, our websites may provide links to other websites owned by third parties. Please note that Mount Holyoke College is not responsible for any of the privacy policies of those websites. We advise that you read their policies for further information.

### Email subscriptions

MHC Today allows you to subscribe online, and receive the MHC Today newsletter via email. If you no longer wish to receive this email, follow the "unsubscribe" instructions located near the bottom of each email.

If you send us email messages, you should be aware that information disclosed in email may not be secure or encrypted and thus may be available to others. We suggest you exercise caution when deciding to disclose any personal or confidential information in email. We will use your email address to respond directly to your questions or comments.

The college reserves the right to continually review and make changes to this privacy statement at any time. Use of our website means you completely understand and consent to the policy outlined above.

If you have any questions regarding this privacy statement or the Mount Holyoke College website, please contact the [Office of Communications](mailto:communications-wm@mtholyoke.edu).
